let phy = [
    {
      question:`Two cars moving in the same direction have speeds of 100 km/h
      and 130 km/h what is the velocity of the faster car as measured by an
      observer in the slower car?`,
      options:[`30 km/h`,`130 km/h`,`200 km/h`,`230 km/h`],
      answer:"30 km/h",
    },
    {
      question:`A car moves with an initial velocity of 25 m/s and reaches a
      velocity of 45 m/s in 10s. what is the acceleration of the car?`,
      options: [`2 m/s<sup>2</sup>`,
      `5 m/s<sup>2<sup>`,
      `20 m/s<sup>2</sup>`,
      `25 m/s<sup>2</sup>`],
      answer:"2 m/s<sup>2</sup>",
    },
    {
      question:`The surfaces of conveyor belts are made rough so as to  `,
      options:[`Protect them while carry loads`,
      `Prevent the loads from slipping`,
      `Enable them to carry more loads`,
      `Make them stronger`],
      answer:`Prevent the loads from slipping`,
    },
    {
      question:`A machine of velocity ratio 6 requires an effort of 400 N to
      raise a load of 800 N through 1 m. Find the efficiency of the machine.`,
      options:["55.6%","50.0%","33.3%","22.2%"],
      answer:"33.3%",
    },
    {
      question:`If a wire 30 cm long is extended to 30.5 cm by a force of 300 N.
      Find the strain energy of the wire.`,
      options:["0.75 J","7.5 J","75.0 J","750.0 J"],
      answer:"0.75 J",
    },
    {
      question:`The accurate measurement of the relative density of a substance
      in its powdered form is done with a beam balance and `,
      options:["A density bottle","Eureka can","A pipette","A burette"],
      answer:"A density bottle",
    },
    {
      question: `A load is pull at a uniform speed along a horizontal floor by a
      rope at 45<sup><i>o</i></sup> to floor. If the force in the rope is 1500N, what
      is the frictional force on the load?`,
      options:["1524 N","1350 N","1260 N","1061 N"],
      answer:"1061 N",
    },
    {
      question:`Calculate the total distance covered by a train before coming to
      rest if its initial speed is 30m/s with a constant retardation of
      0.1m/s<sup>2</sup>`,
      options:[`5500 m`,"4500 m","4200 m","3000 m"],
      answer:"4500 m",
    },
    {
      question:`A rocket is fired from the earth's surface to a distant planet.
      By Newton's law of universal gravitation, the force F will`,
      options:[`Increase as r reduces`,
      `Increase as G varies`,
      `Remains constant`,
      `Increase as r increases`],
      answer:"Increase as r reduces",
    },
    {
      question:`An object moves in a circular path of radius 0.5m with a speed
      of 1m/s What is its angular velocity?`,
      options:["8 rad/s","4 rad/s","2 rad/s","1 rad/s"],
      answer:"2 rad/s",
    },
    {
      question:`An object of mass 20kg slides down an inclined plane at an angle
      of 30<sup>o</sup> to the horizontal. The coefficient of static friction is?[g = 10ms-2]`,
      options:["0.2","0.3","0.5","0.6"],
      answer:"0.6",
    },
    {
      question:`If a load of 1 kg stretches a cord by 1.2cm, what is the force
      constant of the cord? [g=10ms-2]`,
      options:["866 N/m","833 N/m","769 N/m","667 N/m"],
      answer: '833 N/m',
    },
    {
      question:`The equation of a wave traveling in a horizontal direction is
      expressed as y = 15 sin 2/5 (60t - x) what is its wave length?`,
      options:["60 m","15 m","5 m","2 m"],
      answer:"5 m"
    },
    {
      question:`Which of the following factors will affect the velocity of
      sound?`,
      options:[`An increase in the pitch of the sound`,
      `An increase in the loudness of the sound`,
      `Wind travelling in the same direction of the sound`,
      `A change in the atmospheric pressure at constant temperature`],
      answer:`Wind travelling in the same direction of the sound`,
    },
    {
      question:`The characteristic of a vibration that determines its intensity
      is the`,
      options:["Frequency","Overtone","Wavelength","Amplitude"],
      answer:"Amplitude",
    },
    {
      question:`A pinhole camera is placed 300m in front of a building so that
      the image is formed on a screen 5cm from the the pinhole. If the image is
      2.5cm high, the height of the building will be`,
      options:["25 m","50 m","150 m","100 m"],
      answer:"150 m"
    },
    {
      question:`The magnification of an object 2cm tall when placed 10cm in
      front of a plane mirror is`,
      options:["6.0","1.0","0.7","0.6"],
      answer:"1.0",
    },
    {
      question:`After reflection from the concave mirror, rays of light from the
      sun converges`,
      options:[`At the radius of curvature`,
      `At the focus`,
      `Beyond the radius of curvature`,
      `Between the focus and the radius of curvature`],
      answer:`At the focus`,
    },
    {
      question:`A metal rod has a length of 100cm at 200<sup>o</sup> C. At what temperature
      will its length be 99.4cm. If the linear expansivity of the material of
      the rod is 2 x 10<sup>-5</sup> C<sup>-1</sup>`,
      options:[`200<sup>o</sup>C`,
      `300<sup>o</sup>C`,
      `100<sup>o</sup>C`,
      `-100<sup>o</sup>C`],
      answer:`-100<sup>o</sup>C`,
    },
    {
      question:`A train has an initial velocity of 44m/s and an acceleration of
      -4m/s<sup>2</sup>. Calculate its velocity after 10 seconds.`,
      options:["10 m/s","6 m/s","8 m/s","4 m/s"],
      answer:`4 m/s`,
    },
    {
      question:`In a slide wire bridge, the balance is obtained at a point 25cm
      from one end of wire 1m long. The resistance to be tested is connected to
      that end and a standard resistance of 3.6 is connected to the other end of
      the wire. Determine the value of the unknown resistance.`,
      options:["3.2 &#120686;","1.4 &#120686;","3.21 &#120686;","1.2 &#120686;"],
      answer:"1.2 &#120686;",
    },
    {
      question:`A ray of light passes through the centre of curvature of a
      concave mirror and strikes the mirror. At what angle is the ray
      reflected?`,
      options:["180<sup>o</sup>",`90<sup>o</sup>`,`0<sup>o</sup>`,`60<sup>o</sup>`],
      answer:"0<sup>o</sup>"
    },
    {
      question:`The pitch of a screw jack is 0.45cm and the arm is 60cm long. If
      the efficiency of the Jack is 75/œÄ %, calculate the mechanical
      advantage.`,
      options:["400","200","300","150"],
      answer:"200",
    },
    {
      question:`A supply of 400V is connected across capacitors of 3Œºf and 6Œºf
      in series. Calculate the charge.`,
      options:[`8 x 10<sup>-4</sup>C`,
      `4 x 10<sup>-2</sup>C`,
      `8 x 10<sup>-3</sup>C`,
      `4 x 10<sup>-8</sup>C`],
      answer:`8 x 10<sup>-4</sup>C`,
    },
    {
      question:`A vibrator causes water ripples to travel across the surface of
      a tank. The wave travels 50cm in 20s and the distance between successive
      crests is 5cm. Calculate the frequency of the vibrator.`,
      options:["0.5 Hz","6 Hz","5.2 Hz","25 Hz"],
      answer:"0.5 Hz",
    },
    {
      question:`A thermocouple thermometer is connected to a millivoltmeter
      which can read up to 10mV. When one junction is in ice at 0<sup>o</sup>C and the
      other is steam at 100<sup>o</sup>C, the millivoltmeter reads 4mV. What is the maximum
      temperature which this arrangement can measure.`,
      options:[`100<sup>o</sup>C`,
      `248<sup>o</sup>C`,
      `250<sup>o</sup>C`,
      `350<sup>o</sup>C`],
      answer:`250<sup>o</sup>C`
    },
    {
      question:`An alternating current can induce voltage because it has`,
      options:[`Riple value`,
      `Varying magnetic field`,
      `Weaker magnetic field than DC`,
      `Hign peak value`],
      answer:'Varying magnetic field',
    },
    {
      question:`The earth's gravitational field intensity at its surface is
      about?[G = 6.7 x 10<sup>-11</sup>Nm<sup>2</sup>/kg<sup>2</sup>, mass of
      the earth is 6 x 10<sup>24</sup>kg, radius of the earth is 6.4 x 10<sup>6</sup>m, g on the earth =
      9.8m/s<sup>2</sup>].`,
      options:["6.7 N/kg","7.9 N/kg","8.0 N/kg","9.8 N/kg"],
      answer:"9.8 N/kg",
    },
    {
      question:`The force required to make an object of mass m, travelling with
      velocity v, turn in a circle of radius r is`,
      options:[`mv<sup>2</sup>&#x2044;r`,
      `mr<sup>2</sup>&#x2044;x`,
      `mr&#x2044;v`,
      `mv&#x2044;r<sup>2</sup>`],
      answer:`mv<sup>2</sup>&#x2044;r`,
    },
    {
      question:`A machine gun with a mass of 5kg fires a 50g bullet at a speed
      of 100 m/s. Calculate the recoil speed of the machine gun. `,
      options:["0.5 m/s","1.5 m/s",'1.0 m/s',"2.0 m/s"],
      answer:'1.0 m/s'
    },
	  {
		  question:`Red light travel faster than blue light when both of them pass through a glass prism because the `,
		  options:[`refractive index of red light is greater than that of blue light`,
			  `refractive index of blue light is greater than that of red light`,
			  `red light is more intense than the blue light`,
			  `blue light is more intense than the red light`],
		  answer:`red light is more intense than the blue light`,
	  },
	  {
		  question:`All electromagnetic wave in a vacuum have the same `,
		  options: [`wavelength`,`frequency`,`speed`,`amplitude`],
		  answer:`speed`,
	  },
	  {
		  question:`An alternating current supply is connected to an electric lamp which lights with the same brightness as it does with a direct current source of <i>emf</i> 6V. The peak potential difference of the a.c supply is  `,
		  options:[`4.6V`,`6.0V`,`8.5V`,`12.0V`],
		  answer: `8.5V`,

	  },
	  {
		  question: `An electric generator rated 12<i>kW</i>, 2<i>kV</i> distributes power through a cable of resistance 20ùùÆ. Calculate the power loss in the cable.`,
		  options:["120 W", "360 W", "720 W", "2400 W"],
		  answer: "720 W",
	  },
	  {
		  question:`The angle which the direction of the earth magnetic field makes with the horizontal at a place is known as `,
		  options:[`angle of contact`,
			  `angle of dip`,
			  `angle of declination`,
			  `magnetic meridian`],
		  answer: `angle of dip`,
	  },
	  {
		  question:`A force acts on a body for 0.5s changing its momentum from 16.0kg ms<sup>-1</sup> to 21.0 kg ms<sup>-1</sup>. Calculate the magnitude of the force.`,
		  options:["42.0 N","37.0 N","32.0 N",
			  "10.0 N"],
		  answer:"10.0 N",
	  },
	  {
		  question:`A piece metal of relative density 5.0 weighs 60 N in air. Calculate its weight when fully immersed in water.`,
		  options:["4 N","5 N","48 N","60 N"],
		  answer:"48 N",
	  },
	  {
		  question:`The mass of a loaded spiral spring oscillates vertically between two extreme positions P and R equidistant from the equilibrium position Q. Which of the following statements about the system is not correct?`,
		  options:[`The momentum of the mass is maximum at Q`,
			  `The elastic potential energy of the spring is maximum at Q`,
			  `The kinetic energy of the mass is maximum at P`,
			  `The total energy of the system is always constant`],
		  answer:`The momentum of the mass is maximum at Q`,
	  },
	  {
		  question:`A platinum resistance thermometer has a resistance of 4ùùÆ at 0<sup>o</sup>C and 10ùùÆ at 100<sup>o</sup>C. Assuming the resistance changes uniformly with temperature, calculate the resistance of the thermometer when the temperature is 45<sup>o</sup>C.`,
		  options:["14.0 ùùÆ","6.7 ùùÆ","3.2 ùùÆ","2.7 ùùÆ"],
		  answer:"6.7 ùùÆ",
	  },
	  {
		  question:`A metal rod of length 100 cm is heated through 100<sup>o</sup>C, calculte the change in length of the rod.[linear expansivity of the material of the rod is 3 x 10<sup>-5</sup> K<sup>-1</sup>]`,
		  options:["4 mm","3 mm","2 mm","1 mm"],
		  answer:"3 mm",
	  },
	  {
		  question:`Which of the following statements about the characteristics of sound waves is correct?`,
		  options:[`Loudness decreases with increase in intensity`,
			  `The pitch of a note is determined by its amplitude`,
			  `The intensity of a sound wave is proportional to its amplitude`,
			  `The quality of a note depends on its overtone`],
		  answer:`The intensity of a sound wave is proportional to its amplitude`,
	  },
	  {
		  question:`The ability of a material to store an electric charge when its plates are at different potentials is referred to as its `,
		  options:["conductance","inductance","capacitance","resistance"],
		  answer:`capacitance`,
	  },
	  {
		  question:`A constantin wire has a cross sectional area of 4x10<sup>-8</sup> m<sup>2</sup> and a resistivity of 1.1 x 10<sup>-6</sup>ùùÆm. If a resistor of resistance 11ùùÆ is to be made from its wire, calculate the length of the wire required.`,
		  options:["0.4 m","0.8 m","2.5 m","5.0 m"],
		  answer:"0.4 m",
	  },
	  {
		  question:`Light of energy 5.0 eV falls on a metal plate of work function 3.0 eV and electrons are emitted, determined the stopping potential.[electronic charge, e = 1.60 x 10<sup>-19</sup>C]`,
		  options:["1.7 V","2.0 V","8.0 V","15.0 V"],
		  answer:"2.0 V",
	  },
	  {
		  question:`The velocity ratio of an inclined plane, inclined at an angle X to the horizontal can be expressed as `,
		  options:["(sin X)<sup>-1</sup>","sin X","(cos X)<sup>-1</sup>","cos X"],
		  answer:"(sin X)<sup>-1</sup>",
	  },
	  {
		  question:` A quantity of steam at 100<sup>o</sup>C condenses to water at the same temperature by releasing 6.9 x 10<sup>4</sup> J of energy. Calculate the mass of the condensed steam.[specific latent heat of vapourization of water = 2.3 x 10<sup>6</sup> J/kg ]`,
		  options:["3.0 x 10<sup>-1</sup> kg","3.0 x 10<sup>-2</sup> kg","3.0 x 10<sup>-3</sup> kg","3.0 x 10<sup>-4</sup> kg"],
		  answer:"3.0 x 10<sup>-2</sup> kg",
	  },
	  {
		  question:`A note of frequency 2000 Hz has a velocity of 400 m/s. Calculate the wave length of the note`,
		  options:["5.0 m","2.0 m","0.5 m","0.2 m"],
		  answer:"0.2 m",
	  },
	  {
		  question:`Which of the following observations cannot be explained using the rectilinear propagation of light?`,
		  options:[`Production of images by a pinhole camera`,
			  `Production of real images of objects by lenses`,
			  `Formation of annular eclipse`,
			  `Diffraction patterns of light`],
		  answer:`Diffraction patterns of light`,
	  },
	  {
		  question:`A ray from a fixed object is incident on a plane mirror at an angle of 20<sup>o</sup>. If the mirror is rotated through 30<sup>o</sup>, by how many degrees would the reflect ray rotate?`,
		  options:["60<sup>o</sup>",
			  "50<sup>o</sup>",
			  "40<sup>o</sup>",
			  "30<sup>o</sup>"],
		  answer:"60<sup>o</sup>",
	  },
	  {
		  question:`The equivalent capacitance of a 3 ¬µF capacitor and a 6 ¬µF capacitor connected in parallel is `,
		  options:["2.0 ¬µF","3.0 ¬µF","4.5 ¬µF","9.0 ¬µF"], 
		  answer:"9.0 ¬µF", 
	  }, 
	  {
		  question:`A radioactive substance of mass 768 g has a half life of 3 years. After how many years does this substance leave only 6 g undecayed?`,
		  options:["21","18","15","12"],
		  answer:"21" 
	  },


    ];
    console.log(`phy=${phy.length}`);
phy.sort((a,b)=>Math.random() - 0.5);
    for(let item of phy){
      if(!(item.options.includes("All of the above") ||
      item.options.includes("None of the above")))item.options.sort((a,b)=>Math.random()-0.5);
    };
export {phy as default};
